<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<refentry version="5.0-subset Scilab" xml:id="preliminary" xml:lang="en"
          xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
          xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
          xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
          xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
          xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
          xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
          xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <refnamediv>
    <refname>preliminary</refname>

    <refpurpose>This is just a short summary of the terms employed in this
    manual.</refpurpose>
  </refnamediv>

  <refsection>
    <title>Description</title>

    <para>If you are not familiar with finite elements, this should be useful
    (but in any case, you should definitively read the getfem++ project
    documentation).</para>

    <para>The mesh is composed of convexes. What we call convexes can be
    simple line segments, prisms, tetrahedrons, curved triangles, of even
    something which is not convex (in the geometrical sense). They all have an
    associated reference convex: for segments, this will be the [0,1] segment,
    for triangles this will be the canonical triangle (0,0)-(0,1)-(1,0)
    etc...All convexes of the mesh are constructed from the reference convex
    through a geometric transformation. In simple cases (when the convexes are
    simplices for example), this transformation will be linear (hence it is
    easily inverted, which can be a great advantage). In order to define the
    geometric transformation, one defines geometrical nodes on the reference
    convex. The geometrical transformation maps these nodes to the mesh
    nodes.</para>

    <para>On the mesh, one defines a set a basis functions: the FEM. A FEM is
    associated at each convex. The basis functions are also attached to some
    geometrical points (which can be arbitrarily chosen). These points are
    similar to the mesh nodes, but they don't have to be the same (this only
    happens on very simple cases, such as a classical P1 fem on a triangular
    mesh). The set of all basis functions on the mesh forms the basis of a
    vector space, on which the PDE will be solved. These basis functions (and
    their associated geometrical point) are the degrees of freedom (dof). The
    FEM is said to be Lagrangian when each of its basis functions is equal to
    one at its attached geometrical point, and is null at the geometrical
    points of others basis functions. This is an important property as it is
    very easy to interpolate an arbitrary function on the finite elements
    space.</para>

    <para>The finite elements method involves evaluation of integrals of these
    basis functions (or product of basis functions etc...) on convexes (and
    faces of convexes). In simple cases (polynomial basis functions and linear
    geometrical transformation), one can evaluate analytically these
    integrals. In other cases, one has to approximate it, using quadrature
    formulas. Hence, at each convex is attached an integration method along
    with the FEM. If you have to use an approximate integration method, always
    choose carefully its order(i.e. highest degree of the polynomials who are
    exactly integrated with the method) : the degree of the FEM, of the
    polynomial degree of the geometrical transformation, and the nature of the
    elementary matrix have to be taken into account. If you are unsure about
    the appropriate degree, always prefer a high order integration method
    (which will slow down the assembly) to a low order one which will produce
    a useless linear-system.</para>

    <para>The process of construction of a global linear system from integrals
    of basis functions on each convex is the assembly.</para>

    <para>A mesh, with a set of FEM attached to its convexes is called a
    mesh_fem object in GetFEM++.</para>

    <para>A mesh, with a set of integration methods attached to its convexes
    is called a mesh_im object in GetFEM++ (New in getfem 2.0).</para>

    <para>A mesh_fem can be used to approximate scalar fields (heat, pression,
    ..), or vector fields (displacement, electric field, ..). A mesh_im will
    be used to perform numerical integrations on these fields. Most of the
    finite elements implemented in GetFEM++ are scalar (however, TR0 and edges
    elements are also available). Of course, these scalar FEMs can be used to
    approximate each component of a vector field. This is done by setting the
    Qdim of the mesh_fem to the dimension of the vector field (i.e. Qdim=1
    =&gt; scalar field, Qdim=2 =&gt; 2D vector field etc...).</para>

    <para>When solving a PDE, one often has to use more than one FEM. The most
    important one will be of course the one on which is defined the solution
    of the PDE. But most PDEs involve various coefficients, for
    example:</para>

    <para><latex align="center"><![CDATA[\nabla\cdot\left(\lambda\left(x\right)\nabla u\right)=f\left(x\right)]]></latex></para>

    <para>Hence one has to define an FEM for the main unknown u, but also for
    the data λ(x) and f(x) if they are not constant. In order to interpolate
    easily these coefficients in their finite element space, one often choose
    a Lagrangian FEM.</para>

    <para>The convexes, mesh nodes, and dof are all numbered. We sometimes
    refer to the number associated to a convex as its convex id (contracted to
    cvid). Mesh node numbers are also called point id (contracted to pid).
    Faces of convexes do not have a global numbering, but only a local number
    in each convex. Hence functions which need or return a list of faces will
    always use a two-rows matrix, the first one containing convex IDs, and the
    second one containing local face number.</para>

    <para>While the dof are always numbered consecutively, this is not always
    the case for point ids and convex ids, especially if you have removed
    points or convexes from the mesh. To ensure that they form a continuous
    sequence (starting from 1), you have to call gf_mesh_set(m,'optimize
    structure').</para>
  </refsection>

  <refsection>
    <title>See Also</title>

    <simplelist type="inline">
      <member><link linkend="gf_workspace">gf_workspace</link></member>

      <member><link linkend="gf_mesh">gf_mesh</link></member>

      <member><link linkend="gf_fem">gf_fem</link></member>

      <member><link linkend="gf_plot">gf_plot</link></member>
    </simplelist>
  </refsection>

  <refsection>
    <title>Authors</title>

    <para>Y. Collette</para>
  </refsection>
</refentry>
